

Cody Wirth

Software Engineer

Info

Phone

(614) 705-9267

Email

codyrwirth@gmail.com

Profile

I have an immense amount of experience working in the technology industry at startups and titans of industry. Some of the tools and technologies that I work with are: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jasmine, jQuery, Python, Flask, SQL/PostgresQL, Node.JS, Jest, Express.js, Pug.js, React, React-Redux, and Git/Github.

Skills

Python

 \bullet \bullet \bullet

Flask

• • • •

JavaScript

• • • •

React.js

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Node.js

 \bullet

SOL

• • • •

lira

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

HTML

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

CSS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Git

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Redux

• • • • •

Links

Linkedin

Github

Portfolio

Employment History

Software Engineering Residency, Springboard

Jan 2020 − Present Pittsburgh

Built full stack web applications with Python/Flask and JavaScript/React

Designed and developed JSON APIs using Node, Express and SQL

Designed and created optimized pages with HTML, CSS, jQuery

Rendered server side templates with Pug

Authentication and Authorization with bcrypt and JWTs

State management with Redux

Unit testing with Jasmine and integration testing with Jest

Dasher Experience Specialist, DoorDash

May 2019 − Present Pittsburgh

Conducted training sessions for new clients and led on boarding process to ensure Dasher success rate

Worked directly with cross-functional internal and external teams creating and delivering solutions for our application and internal tools

Building out and analyzing data with G Suite and Chartio offering descriptive analysis (KPI Dashboards; daily, weekly, monthly user activity; orientation activity; no-show rates)

Participated in the Activation Specialists Project to help activate Dashers stuck in the activation funnel offering email support to field questions about the platform

Trained new Dasher Experience Specialists in company policy, procedure, and tools such as Chartio, G Suite, Okta, Slack, Zoom, Jira, etc.

Worked a ticketing platform in Salesforce to solve and troubleshoot issues that arise on the DoorDash platform (connectivity issues, password resets, deactivation, pay issues, etc.)

Implementation Consultant, nChannel

Working with the Solutions Delivery Team, I handled standard, and custom designed data migrations from various eCommerce platforms such as BigCommerce, Volusion, and Magento, to Shopify's platform

Configured and facilitated the development of matrices for configurable/hierarchical data structures

Facilitated one-on-one consultative sessions with clients determining the scope of their migration projects, any additional custom work that may be needed, as well as provide project estimates based upon terms of scope, complexity, and resources

Created custom MySQL queries to pull non-standard data from eCommerce database schemas

Structured client's data in a thoughtful manner using XSLT as a means for data mapping preparation

Provisioned MySQL instances and setup database hosting for a variety of clients using Azure

Provided technical assistance and support to clients while working with a variety of API's that allow for seamless cloud-based integration solutions

Researched and reported software defects and logged them into Jira

Diagnosed, researched, and resolved technical issues related to data rendering, data structures, site functionality, data connectivity, API support, hosting, and bugs on both Shopify and nChannel's platform

Web Developer, Zen.io

Built personalized landing pages, blogs, and web forms for local businesses utilizing HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript

Designed and built full stack applications with Python/Django such as a job seeking service for community members, and a video subscription service

Designed and built custom email templates for content and marketing teams utilizing HTML/CSS

Product Development Specialist, Facebook

Worked with Facebook's Product Development Specialist team utilizing Excel to analyze data, utilized pivot tables and statistical techniques to identify trends and patterns emerging in user data, utilizing data visualizations tools such as Tableau

Analyzed and resolved all software bugs or issues in a two day turn around, which improved customer satisfaction

Provided technical expertise to developers experiencing issues, as well as reviewing test cases and user reports of bugs

Gathered and analyzed data in regards to customer insight about current product related versions and releases on mobile platforms

Collaborated with project management, development, and operations management to determine the products future direction, and functionality

Education

Springboard, Software Engineering Bootcamp

Jan 2020 - Present

Keller Graduate School of Management, M.S., Information Systems

Jan 2018 − Present Pittsburgh

Denison University, B.A., Religious Studies

Aug 2011 − Dec 2015 Granville

References

Cody Richards

nChannel

codyrichards@gmail.com (740) 258-2445

Aiden Craig

DoorDash

aiden.craig@doordash.com (361) 585-0349

Noah Johnson

Rokkitwear

nomjohnson@gmail.com (513) 205-9636